# **JOHN SOKOL**

Data Scientist

rendering patient health decisions.

management regarding store KPI's in analytic context.

insights regarding secondary home ownership.

#### CONTACT

JS sokolj.com



609.290.9340



johnsokol11@gmail.com

#### **BACKGROUND**

Data scientist specializing in data visualization, statistics, & machine learning to solve critical business problems.

Build self-service analytics tools by connecting disparate enterprise data using Vertica

SQL queries & Tableau for key stakeholders to determine high risk inpatients & long-

term business implications. Propose implementation of machine learning to aid with

Lead Scriptsync initiative to increase medication pick up compliance by 15%. Prioritize

superior customer service to ensure CVS brand loyalty. Consult with pharmacy

Data mine public records to profile demographics of potential real estate clients.

Manipulate data with Python & build Tableau dashboards that deliver key business

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Data Solutions Architect Business Intelligence & Analytics** AtlantiCare Health System March 2018 - Present

Pharmacy Technician, CPhT CVS Health

April 2014 – Present

**LANGUAGES** 

**Data Science Consultant** RE/MAX of Long Beach Island April 2018 - Present

## **EDUCATION**

Python R/RStudio SQL Tableau

Master of Science in Data Science & Strategic Analytics GPA: 4.00 Stockton University August 2018

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry, Computer Science minor GPA: 3.84 Stockton University | NCAA Track & Field | Resident Assistant May 2017

#### **PACKAGES/ML SKILLS**

#### Python/R

Pandas, NumPy, Sci-kit learn, Keras Tidyverse, ggplot, R Markdown

#### **Machine Learning:**

Classification/Regression

Clustering

Feature engineering

Model selection

#### **PROJECTS**

Python: Predicting Heart Disease with Machine Learning, Analysis of UK Energy Consumption

K-means clustering, perceptron, linear &

logistic regression implementation

Tableau:

Venus Thromboembolism (VTE), Super Bowl

Win Probabilities

#### SELECT COURSEWORK

#### Fall 2017:

Data Exploration, Data Gathering & Warehousing

#### **Spring 2018:**

Machine Learning, Data Visualization

#### **Summer 2018:**

Ethics & Security of Data Science, **Communicating Data Stories**